<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[John Moon's Programming Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-10T23:00:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[3 Month RoR Reverse Engineering]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 week programming bootcamp with Launch Academy]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T22:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;November 11 is the first day of class. This is a high intensity program to teach and push the group to become junior software developers, roughly 1 year epxerience in the Ruby on Rails (RoR) world. </p>


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The reason I chose to attend such a program is because it aligns with my goal of building a successful business from scratch. I want to experience the full spectrum of starting and running a business&hellip; even to it&rsquo;s fall. I&rsquo;ll have to take everything in, for my next business. I was hesitant to drop 10 grand and leave my full time job to this fairytale of a dream and join Launch Academy, where I couldn&rsquo;t find much information about the process, hire rates, and simply information about the quality of the program compared to Dev Bootcamp and App Academy.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My fear quickly dissipated when I heard <a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots/54">Ben Orenstein talk</a> about these popular bootcamps. He said he noticed trends of these popular bootcamps emerging and though it was great. He mentioned that it really wasn&rsquo;t the quality of these bootcamps that makes you a great developer, but your own desire to learn and be great. I&rsquo;m paraphrasing, but that was the gist.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I&rsquo;m exicted to start on Monday and become a great programmer. I want to be the best of the class and I&rsquo;ll work hard to make a mark. Cheer for me :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
