<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[3 Month RoR Reverse Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-17T19:42:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Moon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim and everything else]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/vim-and-everything-else/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-17T19:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/vim-and-everything-else</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Using Vim is one of the most amazingly frustrating, confusing, rewarding, and geeking out feeling ever. If you asked me how to copy something in Vim you were out of luck, because I couldn&rsquo;t even navigate folders and files in vim.</p>

<p>This journey of teaching myself Vim with the help of Eric from LA has been a very rewarding. I still have to use Sublime rarely when I want to copy big chunkcs of code on a chat or my gist page, but give me another week and I am confident I&rsquo;ll figure it out.</p>

<p>Having used Sublime for quite some time now, here are some a list of things that each editor does better.</p>

<h3>Vim</h3>

<ol>
<li>Move around super fast. I installed relative numbers so that I can go to the exact line I want to change.</li>
<li>No mouse. It&rsquo;s self explainatory.</li>
<li>You feel awesome slowly mastering and the in&rsquo;s and out&rsquo;s of the editor.</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t know when the learning curve ceiling ends. I learn something new to improve my day to day coding every days.</li>
</ol>


<h3>Sublime</h3>

<ol>
<li>Super easy to use. Basically no learning curve.</li>
<li>Command-p is a little bit better than Vim&rsquo;s. E.G. Searching for file apple_to_go.rb. In sublime you can type apple to go and it will search for you. In vim you have to pretty much type it exactly how it is. If you put a space between words it won&rsquo;t suggest any results.</li>
<li>Copy and paste is terribly easy.</li>
</ol>


<p>Overall I think it is important to improve and increase your tools in your development toolbox and Vim is definitely a big improvement for me. I see myself working towards understand vim in a deeper level in the up coming weeks. I am excited to see what more I can do with this new found tool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 week programming bootcamp with Launch Academy]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T22:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;November 11 is the first day of class. This is a high intensity program to teach and push the group to become junior software developers, roughly 1 year epxerience in the Ruby on Rails (RoR) world. </p>


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The reason I chose to attend such a program is because it aligns with my goal of building a successful business from scratch. I want to experience the full spectrum of starting and running a business&hellip; even to it&rsquo;s fall. I&rsquo;ll have to take everything in, for my next business. I was hesitant to drop 10 grand and leave my full time job to this fairytale of a dream and join Launch Academy, where I couldn&rsquo;t find much information about the process, hire rates, and simply information about the quality of the program compared to Dev Bootcamp and App Academy.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My fear quickly dissipated when I heard <a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots/54">Ben Orenstein talk</a> about these popular bootcamps. He said he noticed trends of these popular bootcamps emerging and though it was great. He mentioned that it really wasn&rsquo;t the quality of these bootcamps that makes you a great developer, but your own desire to learn and be great. I&rsquo;m paraphrasing, but that was the gist.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I&rsquo;m exicted to start on Monday and become a great programmer. I want to be the best of the class and I&rsquo;ll work hard to make a mark. Cheer for me :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
