<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[3 Month RoR Reverse Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-08T19:54:40-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Moon]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practical Object Oriented Design for Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/12/08/practical-object-oriented-design-for-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-08T18:58:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/12/08/practical-object-oriented-design-for-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past week at Launch Academy we dived into object oriented programming. Here is a definition by <a href="http://www.tutorialspoint.com/ruby/ruby_object_oriented.htm">tutorialspoint</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>Ruby is pure object-oriented language and everything appears to Ruby as
an object. Every value in Ruby is an object, even the most primitive
things: strings, numbers and even true and false. Even a class itself
is an object that is an instance of the Class class.</p></blockquote>

<p>My definition is classes are there to help organize and structure
the program so that it may be easily consumed by others. Todays post is
about <a href="http://www.poodr.com/">POODR</a> that adds on top of my definition. It is a way to organize
and structure program so that it may be easily consumed AND changed as
new features are added.</p>

<p>I love that! As programmers, not only should we be thinking to making a
working app, but also an app that has low replacement cost in the future. The idea is
to write code that is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SOLID_(object-oriented_design">SOLID</a> (Single responsibility, Open-closed, Liskov substitution, Interface segregation, and Dependancy Inversion). I&rsquo;m currently focusing on the single responsibility section of the SOLID. I find it difficult as a programming beginner to write classes that are loosely coupled as I want them to be. I started with classes that were family and knew everything about each other. However, with some easy to implement tricks and tips from the book I am learning to write more loosely coupled programs.</p>

<p>For instance, I wrote a program about a company with many employees, who
wanted to know if their employee owed taxes or was due a refund. My
first instinct was to create a company class and an employee class. I
was having difficulty of instantiating a single employee. The problem
was that I was iterating and saving the employees into a single hash,
then passing the hash to the employee class. This caused 2 problems.
First all my employees were a single instance. Second, because they are
a single instance when I passed in the instance to the Employee class,
the employee class was not reading in 1 employee at a time, but the
whole slob.</p>

<blockquote><p>class Company</p>

<blockquote><p>def load_data(file)</p>

<blockquote><p>employees = []
CSV.foreach(file, :headers => true) do |row|</p>

<blockquote><p>employee = row.to_hash</p>

<p>employees &lt;&lt; employee</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p>

<p>employees</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p>

<p>Employee.new(employees)</p></blockquote>

<p>For an experienced developer the solution was right in front of them. The fix was quite simple. I just needed to change where I was instantiating the object. The previous code changed to the following.</p>

<blockquote><p>class Company</p>

<blockquote><p>self.load_data(file)</p>

<blockquote><p>employees = []
CSV.foreach(file, :headers => true) do |row|</p>

<p>employee = Employee.new(row.to_hash)</p>

<p>employees &lt;&lt; employee</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p>

<p>employees</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p></blockquote>

<p>This instantiates each employee separately as I pull data from the CSV file. Now
when I pass my employee to the Employee class, it will be of 1 instance
of an employee. The benefit is that I won&rsquo;t have to do an iterator in my
employee class but instead I can iterate inside my company class.</p>

<p>Another trick I found very useful was passing in hashes as arguments
instead of a multiple variables. The benefits are that you don&rsquo;t have to
worry about in what order you pass in the arguments. If you don&rsquo;t pass
in a value for a specific instance, you can simply give it a default
value.</p>

<blockquote><p>class Employee</p>

<blockquote><p>def initialize(arguments)</p>

<blockquote><p>@employee = arguments[&lsquo;employee&rsquo;] || &lsquo;missing name&rsquo;
@tax_owed = arguments[&lsquo;tax_owed&rsquo;] || &lsquo;0&rsquo;
@tax_paid = arguments[&lsquo;tax_paid&rsquo;] || &lsquo;0&rsquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p></blockquote>

<p>end</p></blockquote>

<p>Hope you learned something from that. If you have any cool tricks feel
free to share in the comments.</p>

<br>


<p>Happy coding!</p>

<p>John</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Loops and Iteration in Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/24/loops-and-iteration-in-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-24T18:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/24/loops-and-iteration-in-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Going through 2 weeks of bootcamp I can&rsquo;t iterate enough how important iterations and loops are. It is one skill I believe has helped me problem solve above average.
On that note, I would like to teach looping through arrays like I am talking to my former non-techie self.</p>

<p>What is iterations? It is the idea of running a same action to each object of the group.</p>

<blockquote><p>num_array = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]</p>

<p>num_array.each |num|
puts num * 2
end</p></blockquote>

<p>The result is a follows</p>

<blockquote><p>2</p>

<p>4</p>

<p>6</p>

<p>8</p>

<p>10</p>

<p>returns nil</p></blockquote>

<p>Lets break that down. What happened? I have a array called num_array that contains the numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5. I ran the each method to the array.</p>

<p>I chose to use the each method because I think it is one of the most commonly used iterators and one that as a developer should know. The each method is basically pulling out each individual number 1 at a time and displaying the result of the number multiplied by 2.</p>

<p>The results are not stored because I used puts. The returned value is nil in this case.</p>

<h4>Notable iteration methods</h4>

<blockquote><p>map, each, each_with_index, inject, and select</p></blockquote>

<p>This of course is not the full list of iteration methods, but one&rsquo;s that I find myself using frequently. If you have any questions feel free to contact me @johnmoon6. Follow me on Github &ndash; jmoon90.</p>

<p>If you want to read more about iterations I recommend you check <a href="http://www.skorks.com/2009/09/a-wealth-of-ruby-loops-and-iterators/">Alan Skorkin&rsquo;s</a> out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breakable Toy - StudyTogether]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/breakable-toy-studytogether/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-22T21:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/22/breakable-toy-studytogether</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>StudyTogether is a website where those who want to study with other people can come and join or create a study group. I tried learning Ruby and Ruby on Rails alone. I tried tutorials. I tried books. It was difficult, and I didn&rsquo;t gain much from it. The problem with self-studying and online studying is that there are endless sources of information, but no one to talk with.</p>

<p>My breakable toy will create study buddies. Other people who are going through the same studying material will be able to talk out problems, teach each other, and learn from the group members mistake. I am going to create a space for users to collaborate on their learning. Something like Khan academy.</p>

<p>Through my experience at Launch Academy, this idea is becoming more and more relevant. I noticed how my learning curb has spiked and is acclerating as I am surrounding with people who are passionate and wanting to learn Ruby on Rails. I will try to incorporate aspects of what I believe to work well in learning in a group environment.</p>

<p>Code On.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ask Google through your Terminal]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/ask-google-through-your-terminal/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-17T19:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/ask-google-through-your-terminal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During my first week at Launch Acadmey I built a simple ruby script so that I don&rsquo;t have to leave my keyboard to ask a question through google. I call it NoMouse.</p>

<p>The idea came when Johnny, one of my mentors at LaunchAcademy, taught me that everything we do in our GUI can be done through the terminal. This was a very interesting and cool concept as a beginner. I wanted to test this theory out. I wanted to see if I can open up my browser from the terminal and open a specific page.</p>

<p>Here is how I tackled the theory. I needed to first figure out how to open a browser or website through my terminal.</p>

<blockquote><p>open &ldquo;<a href="http://www.google.com">http://www.google.com</a>&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>This was possible. Now I need to know if I can run a script and open a browser. In my terminal I ran ruby browser.rb and it would run the following script.</p>

<blockquote><p>system(&ldquo;open&rdquo;, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.google.com">http://www.google.com</a>&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>

<p>This opened up possibilities for me. I was becoming greedy! Not only could I open a browser I wanted to see if I can feed a question to the script for it to search.</p>

<p>I needed to figure out what goes after &ldquo;.com/&rdquo; for google to search. I went to google and typed in a search. How to play basketball.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="https://www.google.com/#q=how+to+play+basketball">https://www.google.com/#q=how+to+play+basketball</a></p></blockquote>

<p>The important part of the link is everything following the &ldquo;.com/&rdquo; Google uses &ldquo;#q=&rdquo; and a &ldquo;+&rdquo; symbol for every space. Simply add the &ldquo;#q=&rdquo; to the system and then create a variable to substitute spaces for &ldquo;+&rdquo; symbols.</p>

<blockquote><p>text = gets.chomp
text.gsub!(&ldquo; &rdquo;,&ldquo;+&rdquo;)
system(&ldquo;open&rdquo;, &ldquo;<a href="http://www.google.com/#q=text">http://www.google.com/#q=text</a>&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>

<p>Ideally, this would turn all the white spaces to a &lsquo;+&ldquo; and we start with the &rsquo;/#q=.&lsquo; It is exact to the google search. This did not work. The # kept changing into &rsquo;%23&#8217; when opens the google browser. When I type &#8220;How do I play basketball?&rdquo; =></p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.google.com/%23q=%7BURI.escape">http://www.google.com/%23q=%7BURI.escape</a>(@question)%7D
It also leads to an error page. The browser is encoding # => %23. I had such a hard time figuring out how to either solve or get around this problme. I figured that there was no way of me to control google from changing # into %23. I needed another solution.</p></blockquote>

<p>Breaking what I have done is found another way google searches. The escape method defined in the ruby doc, &ldquo;Escapes the string, replacing all unsafe characters with code.&rdquo; Basically when i input a question with all the &lsquo;unsafe&rsquo; symbols, and spaces with safe code Here is my final code.</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=#">http://www.google.com/search?q=#</a>{URI.escape(@question)}</p></blockquote>

<h4>Lastly, if you have any recommendations for me to improve this script or a vision of where you think this could go. Please feel free to share with me at my twitter handle. &ndash; @johnmoon6</h4>

<h4><a href="https://github.com/jmoon90/nomouse">Visit the repo</a></h4>

<p>The idea is that I run the nomouse.rb script and it will prompt a message, &lsquo;What is your question?&rsquo; then the user will input a question they have. This triggers your default browser to open and google search the question.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vim and everything else]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/vim-and-everything-else/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-17T19:09:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/vim-and-everything-else</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Using Vim is one of the most amazingly frustrating, confusing, rewarding, and geeking out feeling ever. If you asked me how to copy something in Vim you were out of luck, because I couldn&rsquo;t even navigate folders and files in vim.</p>

<p>This journey of teaching myself Vim with the help of Eric from LA has been a very rewarding. I still have to use Sublime rarely when I want to copy big chunkcs of code on a chat or my gist page, but give me another week and I am confident I&rsquo;ll figure it out.</p>

<p>Having used Sublime for quite some time now, here are some a list of things that each editor does better.</p>

<h3>Vim</h3>

<ol>
<li>Move around super fast. I installed relative numbers so that I can go to the exact line I want to change.</li>
<li>No mouse. It&rsquo;s self explainatory.</li>
<li>You feel awesome slowly mastering and the in&rsquo;s and out&rsquo;s of the editor.</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t know when the learning curve ceiling ends. I learn something new to improve my day to day coding every days.</li>
</ol>


<h3>Sublime</h3>

<ol>
<li>Super easy to use. Basically no learning curve.</li>
<li>Command-p is a little bit better than Vim&rsquo;s. E.G. Searching for file apple_to_go.rb. In sublime you can type apple to go and it will search for you. In vim you have to pretty much type it exactly how it is. If you put a space between words it won&rsquo;t suggest any results.</li>
<li>Copy and paste is terribly easy.</li>
</ol>


<h3>Quick tips to learning Vim</h3>

<ol>
<li>Read vimtutor in your terminal</li>
<li>Watch how people move around files. Through videos, mentor, or friend.</li>
<li>Learn how to move around. I find this the most important part in Vim. You want to jump lines, words, paragraphs, and screens comfortably and efficiently, less key strokes the better.</li>
<li>Keep going at it. It gets easier and becomes fun getting things right!</li>
</ol>


<p>Overall I think it is important to improve and increase the tools in your development toolbox and Vim is definitely a big improvement for me. I see myself working towards understand vim in a deeper level in the upcoming weeks. I am excited to see what more I can do with this new found tool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 week programming bootcamp with Launch Academy]]></title>
    <link href="http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T22:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jmoon90.github.io/blog/2013/11/05/10-week-programming-bootcamp-with-launcha-academy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;November 11 is the first day of class. This is a high intensity program to teach and push the group to become junior software developers, roughly 1 year epxerience in the Ruby on Rails (RoR) world. </p>


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The reason I chose to attend such a program is because it aligns with my goal of building a successful business from scratch. I want to experience the full spectrum of starting and running a business&hellip; even to it&rsquo;s fall. I&rsquo;ll have to take everything in, for my next business. I was hesitant to drop 10 grand and leave my full time job to this fairytale of a dream and join Launch Academy, where I couldn&rsquo;t find much information about the process, hire rates, and simply information about the quality of the program compared to Dev Bootcamp and App Academy.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My fear quickly dissipated when I heard <a href="http://podcasts.thoughtbot.com/giantrobots/54">Ben Orenstein talk</a> about these popular bootcamps. He said he noticed trends of these popular bootcamps emerging and though it was great. He mentioned that it really wasn&rsquo;t the quality of these bootcamps that makes you a great developer, but your own desire to learn and be great. I&rsquo;m paraphrasing, but that was the gist.</p>

<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I&rsquo;m exicted to start on Monday and become a great programmer. I want to be the best of the class and I&rsquo;ll work hard to make a mark. Cheer for me :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
